<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on A blog to document my foray into analytics and machine learning</title>
    <link>/rlouden.netlify.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on A blog to document my foray into analytics and machine learning</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/rlouden.netlify.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Another Note on A blogdown Tutorial</title>
      <link>/rlouden.netlify.com/note/another-note/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/rlouden.netlify.com/note/another-note/</guid>
      <description>I just discovered an awesome tutorial on blogdown written by Alison. I have to admit this is the best blogdown tutorial I have seen so far.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Quick Note on Two Beautiful Websites</title>
      <link>/rlouden.netlify.com/note/a-quick-note/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/rlouden.netlify.com/note/a-quick-note/</guid>
      <description>To me, the two most impressive websites based on blogdown are:
 Rob J Hyndman&amp;rsquo;s personal website. Live Free or Dichotomize by Lucy and Nick et al.  I&amp;rsquo;m sure there will be more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Hugo XMin</title>
      <link>/rlouden.netlify.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/rlouden.netlify.com/about/</guid>
      <description>XMin is the first Hugo theme I have designed. The original reason that I wrote it was I needed a minimal example of Hugo themes when I was writing the blogdown book. Basically I wanted a simple theme that supports a navigation menu, a home page, other single pages, lists of pages, blog posts, categories, tags, and RSS. That is all. Nothing fancy. In terms of CSS and JavaScript, I really want to keep them minimal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EDA &amp; model building</title>
      <link>/rlouden.netlify.com/post/2019-04-14-football-modelling-part-2-eda-and-modelling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/rlouden.netlify.com/post/2019-04-14-football-modelling-part-2-eda-and-modelling/</guid>
      <description>####This markdown document will serve as part two, focussing on exploring the data collected in part one and building the final model to test on player data, as such it will be focussed at the team level.
As before, first thing to do is load the required packages, for this piece the requirements should be filled by both the tidyverse and tidymodels packages, as well as the required model packages and ggrepel / gghighlight to add tweaks to charts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EPL scraping</title>
      <link>/rlouden.netlify.com/post/2019-04-14-football-modelling-part-1-data-collection/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/rlouden.netlify.com/post/2019-04-14-football-modelling-part-1-data-collection/</guid>
      <description>###This piece of work will focus on scraping football data and using it to build a statistical model to predict the outcomes of premier league matches in England. It will be comprised of three parts, all aiming to use skills I have acquired over the past couple of years.
Part one: Obtaining data on both current players (past three years) and teams for the last four seasons of matches</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>